Young Hyun Yoo

Software Engineer

Email: softluster4753@gmail.com

Mobile: +82-10-3023-6720

Summary

An adaptable professional with extensive experience across multiple domains. Expert in back-end web server development, particularly in billing systems, and proficient in front-end development with React (JSX, TypeScript). Completed a Master's degree in Natural Language Processing (funded by Samsung Electronics) and has a paper accepted at ACL 2024. Previously developed bootloaders and device drivers as a system engineer in the BSP team.

Programming Skills

- Languages: Java, C++, Python, SQL, Shell script, Terraform HCL, HTML/CSS/JavaScript (JSX, TypeScript)
- Tools: Spring (MVC, WebFlux, JPA, Security), AWS (ECS, EKS), MySQL, React, PyTorch, HuggingFace, LangChain/LangGraph, SoapUI
- Others: RESTful API, HTTP/TLS, OOP/OOAD/DDD, TDD, Clean coding, Scrum, PCI-DSS, Git/SVN

EXPERIENCE

Agentic AI Chatbot — Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.

Suwon, Korea

Staff Engineer

Mar 2024 - Present

o On-device Virtual Assistant using AWS bedrock, LangChain/LangGraph

Sentence Representation Learning Research — Hanyang University

Seoul, Korea

Researcher

Jun 2022 – Feb 2024

- Analyzed and developed efficient methodologies for learning high-quality sentence representations based on large-scale language models.
 - Published Hyper-CL: Conditioning Sentence Representations with Hypernetworks
 - Published Comparison and Analysis of Unsupervised Contrastive Learning Approaches for Korean Sentence Representations

Billing Development — Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.

Suwon, Korea

Engineer

Nov 2016 - Mar 2022

- Led CP portal redevelopment using React, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, and JPA (2020-2022)
- o Developed DSA agreement feature (2021)
- Developed a subscription product change feature for active subscriptions (2021)
- Implemented 3DS2 compliance for EU PSD2 regulations (2020)
- Developed remote login to Samsung Smart TV using a smartphone (2020)
- Developed an integration test framework using SoapUI and Groovy (2019)
- o Migrated buyer portal from monolithic architecture to MSA using AWS ECS and Terraform HCL (2019)
- Re-architected the Billing service for PCI-DSS (2018)
- o Led buyer portal redevelopment using React, Spring Boot, and JPA (2018)

BSP Development — Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.

Suwon, Korea

Engineer

Feb 2015 - Nov 2016

• Ported the ramdump feature to the Samsung Smart TV kernel (2016)

Samsung Software Membership

Suwon, Korea

Under graduate

Feb 2013 - Feb 2015

- Modified the Android kernel to operate a smartphone as a webcam, speaker, and microphone
 - Selected as the best project of the year (http://bit.ly/358b7O8)

EDUCATION

Hanyang University

Seoul, Korea

Master of Science in Computer Science; GPA: 4.06/4.5

Mar 2022 - Feb 2024

Hongik University

Seoul, Korea

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering; GPA: 3.5/4.5

Mar 2008 - Feb 2015

Publications

- Young Hyun Yoo, Jii Cha, Changhyeon Kim and Taeuk Kim, Hyper-CL: Conditioning Sentence Representations with Hypernetworks, *The 62nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics* (ACL 2024).
- Young Hyun Yoo, Kyumin Lee, Minjin Jeon, Jii Cha, Kangsan Kim, and Taeuk Kim, Comparison and Analysis of Unsupervised Contrastive Learning Approaches for Korean Sentence Representations, *The 34th Annual Conference on Human and Cognitive Language Technology* (HCLT 2022).

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

• Achievements

• Selected as a core talent by Samsung Core Talent Management (2022-present)

• Languages

o English: Proficient, Korean: Native